<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>cmlzaGk - bookreview</title><link href="https://cmlzagk.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cmlzagk.github.io/feeds/bookreview.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cmlzagk.github.io/</id><updated>2021-12-10T20:44:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Book Review - Beyond The Gender Binary</title><link href="https://cmlzagk.github.io/beyond-the-gender-binary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-10T20:44:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-10T20:44:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Rishi Maker</name></author><id>tag:cmlzagk.github.io,2021-12-10:/beyond-the-gender-binary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book review of Beyond The Gender Binary&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Beyond the gender binary” is a pocketbook by Alok Vaid-Menon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a short, single-chapter, 65 page book, and took a little over an hour for me to complete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was encouraged to read the book by a colleague to develop awareness of the LGBTQIA+ community and learn off their daily experiences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of the book speaks about the author’s evolution and experience as a gender non-conforming trans feminine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half addresses arguments against gender non-conforming people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beyond The Gender Binary" src="/images/beyondthegenderbinary.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Structure And Style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book points out that for many things, we focus on the topic (gender fluidity), without ever focusing on experiences of people living it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half attempts to bridge the gap by sharing the experience of the author. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It questions the power structure of the society and institutions, and do they really encourage people to be different, or only different to a point where it allows them to place people in boxes without making things uncomfortable for the institutions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half of the book addresses common talking-points against gender non-conforming people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part of the book is well structured. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arguments are categorized into four categories – Dismissal, Inconvenience, Biology and Slippery Slope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author creates a sub-topic from a talking point and provides their analysis of the sub-topic, where it originates from and why they think its flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is very easy to read, clear, concise and to the point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative is relatable, with author occasionally putting a humorous and witty twist to keep the reader engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is thought provoking. While the conversation is about gender non-conforming people, a lot of discussion also applies to a broader spectrum of the society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the short nature of the book, it was a perfect first book to begin a journey to learn about LGBTQIA+ for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Purchase &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beyond-Gender-Binary-Pocket-Collective/dp/B086P7JKKB"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="bookreview"></category><category term="dni"></category></entry></feed>